Dr. Jimmye S. Hillman Papers 1933-2007
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1933-1995; Series II
  - Water and Public Policy, 1933 - 1990; Subseries I
    - The Value of Colorado River Water for Agricultural Uses in Central Arizona, undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Water and Public Policy, undated (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Commission on Food and Fiber, 1965 - 1980; Subseries II
    In chronological order, this subseries is comprised of reports, papers, and correspondence in relation to the President’s National Advisory Commission on Food and Fiber, which Dr. Hillman was appointed to as Executive Director during 1966 – 1967.
    - Food and Fiber - Commission Background, 1965 - 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Abstract of the Proceedings of the Meeting of the National Advisory Commission on Food and Fiber, Washington, D.C., January 11, 1966 – January 13, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Stenographic Transcript, General Services Administration, January, 11, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Stenographic Transcript, General Services Administration, January, 12, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stenographic Transcript, General Services Administration, January, 13, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Abstract of the Proceedings of the Meeting of the National Advisory Commission on Food and Fiber, Washington, D.C., March 24, 1966 – March 25, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Transcript of the Public Hearing in Dallas, Texas, April 13, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Food and Fiber - Initial Background, 1966 - 1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Food and Fiber - Hillman Speech Material, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Food and Fiber - TV Tape Cutting Commission Report, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Other Consulting Work, 1954 - 1995; Subseries III
    Arranged in chronological order, this subseries is comprised of notes, papers, correspondence focused on consulting work and various personal work that Dr. Hillman did over the years. Some of work includes the consulting work he provided for USAID in Brazil, agricultural policy advising for Portugal, chairing the President’s Commission on US-Japanese Relations, as well as his sabbatical work in New Zealand and Visiting Fellow/Professor appointments outside of the US.
    - USDA-Agricultural Marketing Research Division Movement and Merchandising of Milk, 1954 – 1955 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Argentina Farm Management Course - Buenos Aires, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Foreign Policy Workshop – US and Latin America (OAS) Meeting in Tucson, April 28, 1960 – May 1, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - International Course on Research Methods in Agricultural Marketing – Chile, June 21, 1960 – August 12, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - University of Ceara, Brazil – Sponsored by USAID/Brazil and the Brazilian Government, 1965 – 1966 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Red Bluff Water District Report and Related Data – Pecos, Texas, April 1, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - ILMA – Bogota, Columbia – Reports and Related Data, July 1968 – December 1968 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Forms and Directives Related to Federal Executive and Official Duty in Washington, D.C., 1968- 1971 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - ILMA – Bogota, Colombia – Lectures, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Northeast Brazil – RRNA/IBRD, 1969 – 1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Northeast Brazil – Reports and Related Data, RRNA/IBRD, 1969 – 1970 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Ad Hoc Expert Consultation on Teaching in Agricultural Marketing at the University Level, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Study on Agricultural Economics at the National University of Zaire, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - FAO Adjustment Studies – Agricultural Policies and Trade, 1972 – 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - FAO Reports on International Agricultural Adjustment, Trade Negotiations, Domestic/International, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Reports prepared for FAO, Rome, World Food Security, International Agricultural Adjustment, etc., 1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - FAO/Rome, 1976 – 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - FAO Conference on Progress of International Agricultural Adjustment Report, August 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Evaluation of Doctoral Program – Louisiana State University, July 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - FAO/Rome – Agriculture Towards 2000, 1978 – 1979 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Poland Visit and Producers Livestock Marketing Association, 1980 - 1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - AAEA Presidency and Related Data, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - USDA Special Honor Award, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - US-Japan Advisory Commission - Presidential Committee on Agricultural Study Group Initial Data, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - California PIK Lettuce Consultation, 1983 – 1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - American University of Cairo and University of Arizona on Desert Development Project, 1983 – 1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - United States – Japan Advisory Commission Report – Conflict and Comity. The State of Agricultural Trade Relations Between the United States and Japan, September 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Statistical Support Services for AgEcon Department, 1984 – 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - FAO/Rome Sponsored Attendance at Zimbabwe Workshop on Production Statistics, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical - Miscellaneous, 1987 – 1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical – Meetings and Personal Contacts, 1989 – 1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - New Zealand Sabbatical Leave Report, 1990 – 1991 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Central Arizona Project, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - US Department of Education Consultation, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - New Zealand Seminars and Related Data to Fulbright Program, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Area Studies Latin America, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - International Programs, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Latin American and Brazilian Special Studies (1 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Latin American and Brazilian Special Studies (2 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Latin American and Brazilian Special Studies (3 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Latin American and Brazilian Special Studies (4 of 4), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - P.L. 480 in Brazil and Surplus Disposal, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - University of Arizona Administrative Files, 1948 - 1993; Subseries IV
    Listed in chronological order, this subseries is comprised of notes, reports, and various administrative materials in relation to Dr. Hillman’s tenure as a Professor of Agricultural Economics for the University of Arizona – College of Agricultural and Life Sciences.
    - Agricultural Economics 101A Lecture Notes, September 1947 – February 1948 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Economics 122, February 1948 – June 1948 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Agricultural Economics 1 Notes - University of Arizona, September 1954 – February 1955 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - University of Arizona – Administration, 1959 – 1970 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Agricultural Economics Staff Meetings, Etc., 1961 – 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Salary/Budget Propaganda, 1963 – 1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Lecture for Biological Sciences 221 – The World Food Problem Myth and Reality, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hillman Lecture Notes for AEC 102 and AEC 042, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Long Range Plans, Budget, Etc., 1981 – 1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Endowment Draft Letters, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Endowment Address List, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Endowment, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Hillman Lecture Notes for AEC 102, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Marketing of Ranch and Farm Products - Economics 203 Notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Scholarly Files, 1947-2007; Series III
  The series is comprised of the scholarly activities that Dr. Hillman participated in during his career.
  - Speeches and Publications, 1946-2007; Subseries I
    In chronological order, this subseries is comprised of articles, speeches, and papers written by Dr. Hillman that predominately focus on agricultural policy and tariff and trade policies.
    - Economics of the Tung Oil Industry in the United States, March 1946 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Agricultural Market Control Under Federal Statues, October 1947 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - The International Wheat Agreements, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Articles, 1952 – 1954 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Barriers to the Interstate Movement of Agricultural Products by Motor Vehicle in the Eleven Western States, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Barriers to the Interstate Movement of Milk and Dairy Products in the Eleven Western States, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Restrictions on the Production and Interstate Distribution of Margarine in the Eleven Western States, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Area Shifts in the Western Lettuce Industry – The California Story..., October 1955 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Impact and Problems of Export Programs, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Review of A Foreign Economic Policy for the US, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - O Desenvolvimento Economico E O Nordeste Brasileiro, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Hillman Speeches, 1958 – 1966 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Some Aspects of Brazilian Agricultural Policy, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Collins' Changing Role of Price - Notes and Comments, August 1959 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - United States Agricultural Surplus Disposal – A Case Study: Brazil, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Minor articles, 1959 – 1964 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - The Peril Point and Section 22 Provisions – Asset of Liability, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Relation Between Composition and Consumer Acceptance of Milk Beverages, July 1960 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Relation Between Composition and Consumer Acceptance of Milk Beverages, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Review of Article "Collin's Changing Role of Price", 1960 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - The Welfare State in New Zealand, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Increasing Agricultural Productivity in Underdeveloped Countries, 1960 – 1963 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Problems of Increasing Agricultural Productivity in Less Advanced Countries, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Educational Needs in Latin America, 1961 – 1964 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Come aumentare la produttivita agricola nei paesi sottossvgiluppati, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Surpluses – Burden or Asset?, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Economic Forces Affecting Trends in Milk Composition, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Suggested Modifications in Public Law 480, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Economic Potentials of the Papago Indians of Arizona, 1963 – 1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Surplus Disposal and Supply Control, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Attempts to Expand Agricultural Exports Through United States Government Action, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - I Programmi di Esportazione di Beni Agricoli E La Bilancia Dei Pagamenti Degli Stati Uniti, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Agricultural Surpluses? Arizona's Share is Small, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - A Further Look at P.L. 480 and the Balance of Payments, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Governor Goddard's Advisory Committee on Seasonal Farm Labor, 1965 – 1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Food and Fiber Policy for a Changing Agriculture", 1967 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Social and Political Dilemma of the Agricultural Industry and Agricultural Institutions, July 22, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Statement before the House Committee on Ways and Means - Public Hearing on Tariff and Trade Proposals, June 13, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Task Force Data on Foreign Agricultural Trade and Economic Development, 1968 – 1969 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Speeches/Participation - Papers, Newspaper Articles/Meetings and Seminars, 1968 – 1971 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Agricultural Subsistence and Market Production in Developing Countries: A Colombian Case Study, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - United States Trade with Mexico, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - On Returning from Our Agricultural Babel, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Problems of Agri-Management, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Can PCA's Meet the Challenge of the '70s?, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Farm Organization, Management, and Financing in the Years Ahead, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Increasing Agricultural Productivity vs Environmental Protection in Developing Countries: Analyses of Alternatives, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Finding a Future for the U.S. Cotton Producer: An Economic Study of His Problems and Opportunities - National Cotton Council of America, March 1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - The Economist at Bay, April 27, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Farm Labor and Agriculture, statement before meetings sponsored by the Arizona Ecumenical Council, July 1972 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Elements of a national land use policy, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - The Professional Nutritionist, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Agricultural Protection: Domestic Policy and International Trade, November 10, 1973 – November 29, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - The Impact of an International Food Bank, December 1973 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Speeches in Oxford, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Toward the Integration of World Agriculture, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Statement on "International Trade and Western Agriculture", March 1974 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - High Food Prices: The Tip of an Iceberg, May 1974 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - FAO Committee on Commodity Problems - Agricultural Protection: Domestic Policy and International Trade, October 14, 1974 – October 25, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Agricultural Protection: Domestic Policy and International Trade, October 1974 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - World Agriculture in Disarray Book Review, November 1974 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Protein Efficiencies of High-Protein Products and Processes Paper for AlChE Meeting, December 1, 1974 – December 5, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Non-tariff Trade Barriers in Agriculture, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Trade Liberalization: Obstacles and Prospects Paper Presented at WAEA Meeting, July 20, 1975 – July 22, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Land Needs for Food and Fiber with a Population of Six Billion, August 1975 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Issues in World Food Production and Trade: Their Relevance for Arizona Agriculture, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Report of the Western Assembly on Population and Hunger, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Think you can Fight Arab Oil with US Grain? No Way!, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Trade and Aid: Trends and Issues with Emphasis on the Impact of Trade on Agricultural Stability in the US – Paper presented at WAERC, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Types of Non-Tariff Restrictions Speech, March 1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - National Self-Sufficiency in Food, November 1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Discussion: Growth Rates and Economic Development, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Statement Before the Joint Economic Committee, January 1977 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 160 Acres and Mule?, October 1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Food Enough for All, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Agricultural Protection: An Observation and Warning, December 1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Agri-Power Food – The Ultimate Weapon?, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - The Importance of International Trade to Arizona's Agricultural and Rural Economy, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Nontariff Barriers: Major Problem in Agricultural Trade, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Why Agricultural Trade Barriers Should Be Lowered, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Trends and Developments in the Meat and Livestock Industries Talk, January 31, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Bending Trends and Developments in the Meat and Livestock Industries, August 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Future of Livestock and Meat Industry: Political, Cultural, and International Factors Must Be Weighed", 1979 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - International Trade Arrangements, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Nontariff Agricultural Trade Barriers Book Reviews, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Policy Issues Relevant to US Agricultural Trade, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Research Needs and Research Results in International Agricultural Trade, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - State Intervention and State Trading: Observations by an Agricultural Economist on a New Mode of Agricultural Protectionism, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - United States Agricultural Policy and Prospects Lecture, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Animal Agriculture Research to Meet Human Needs in the 21st Century, May 1980 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Theodore Heidhues Memorial Seminar Papers, November 6, 1980 – November 8, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - International Agricultural Trade Policy and Related Issues, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Mexico's Agricultural Dilemma, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Trade Protectionism and Agriculture, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Trends and Developments in the Meat and Livestock Industries, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - US Agricultural Trade Policy Evolution and European Interaction, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - The Role of Export Cropping in Less Developed Countries, May 1981 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Agricultural Export Dumping: The Case of Mexican Winter Vegetables in the US Market, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Arizona's Foreign Agricultural Markets, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Food Policy and International Trade Issues for the 1980s, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - The Outlook for Food Exports to Industrialized Countries, February 14, 1982 – February 15, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Global Inflation: Is There a Cure? Presentation at Great Decisions - Central Arizona College, March 21, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Farming and Ranching 1982 and Beyond: A Policy Overview Talk to Arizona Farm Bureau, July 28, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Agricultural Technology Innovation and Transfer in an International Setting Paper for IAAE Conference, August 24, 1982 – September 2, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Impact of the Changing World Situation on United States Agriculture Speech, November 12, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - International Trade Arrangements, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Statement to Select Committee on Economic Development - Arizona House of Representatives, May 24, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Agricultural Policy and Development - Lisbon, Portugal, June 28, 1983 – June 29, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Arizona and the US Foreign Trade in Agricultural Commodities, June 1983 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Technical Change, Protectionism, and Market Structure: The Case of International Trade in Fresh Winter Vegetables, August 1983 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - FASB Statement No. 33: Misleading Information on Inflation-Adjusted Income, September 1983 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Financial Indicators Evince Economics and Diseconomies of Size in US Farming, December 1983 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Measuring the Importance of United States Agricultural Exports, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Research Proposal, Miscellaneous Papers re Agricultural Policies, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - US and EC Agricultural Trade Policies: Confrontation or Negotiation?, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Comments to the National Council of State Legislatures - Denver, Colorado, February 18, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - United States Agricultural Policy 1985 and Beyond, March 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Remarks to the Southern California Agribusiness Outlook and Issues Conference, May 30, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Testimony on Senator Goldwater's Bill on Taxes on Purchase of US Land by Foreigners, June 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Financial Stress in Agriculture Workshop, October 22, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Gearing Up for 1985 Paper, October 1984 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Inconsistencies in US Trade and agricultural policies Vis-a-Vis Our Major Trading Partners Talk before the National Planning Administration, November 9, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Agricultural Protectionism: Precursor of New Trade Wars, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Conflict and Comity - The State of Agricultural Trade Relations Between the US and Japan - US-Japan Advisory Commission”, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - International Trade Environment for Food and Agriculture in the Late 1980s, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Trade and the US Food and Fiber System, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Review of the Role of Markets in the World Food Economy, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Triennial Congress of the EAAE - Influence of Technical Change on Future US Beef Exports to the EEC, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Wider Implications of Protecting Japan's Rice Farmers, March 1985 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Understanding United States Mexican Agricultural Trade, July 1985 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Agricultural and Trade Policies of Other Countries Speech Before the National Commission on Agricultural Trade and Export Policy - Denver, Colorado, August 12, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - More Squeeze Ahead, November 23, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Non-Tariff Trade Barriers: Will They Force US Cattlemen to Change Their Feeding Programs?, January 1986 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Inconsistencies in US Trade and Agricultural Policies Vis-a-Vis its Major Trading Partners, November 2, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - New Era for Agricultural and Trade Policies, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Export Cropping and Desert Agricultural Development Paper at the International Conference in Desert Development, January 25, 1987 – January 31, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Rent Seeking in International Trade: The Great Tomato War, February 1987 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Social Sciences in a Global Context Remarks at SSAP Meeting, June 9, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Embargoes and the Emergence of Brazil's Soybean Industry, September 1987 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Fostering Trade in a Hostile International Environment - Discussion, December 1987 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Brazilian Soybeans: Agribusiness Miracle, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Does '85 Farm Bill Send Wrong Signals?, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Domestic and Export Demand for US Agricultural Products Discussion, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Nontariff Barriers: New Types of Agricultural Protection, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Nontariff Barriers: New Types of Agricultural Protection, April 5, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - US Foreign Trade Policy – The Montevideo Round and Beyond, November 26, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Mexico and United States Agriculture: Conflicts, Opportunities, and Outlook Speech at American Farm Bureau Fed., January 10, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - The Role of Food Policy and Agricultural Products in the Economic Development of Cape Verde Paper Presented at 19th EAAE Seminar, May 29, 1989 – June 2, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Public Choice and Agriculture: An American Example Paper at 9th World Congress of International Economics Association, August 28, 1989 – September 1, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - New Issues and New Constituencies for American Agriculture - Speech Given to Sun City Food and Ag Club, November 8, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Agricultural Constituencies and Agricultural Institute in the US: Implications and Obstacles for a Needed Reform, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Agricultural Trade Between the US and Mexico - The Impacts of Mexico's Foreign Debt, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Economic Aspects of Agricultural Irrigation and Irrigation Research in the USA – Presentation at the XX Meeting of the Centro Studi di Estimo e di Econ, March 2, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - The Evolution of US Agricultural and Trade Policy Speech Before 4th Annual Convention of the American Alfalfa Professors Association, March 4, 1990 – March 7, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)